oneonta.edu 2014-06-17

# Oneonta.edu's Commitment to Privacy

Oneonta.edu's Commitment to Privacy
At the State University of New York College at Oneonta (SUNY Oneonta), we are committed to
protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to
interact with SUNY Oneonta. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be
confident that their privacy is protected when they visit oneonta.edu. You can travel through
most of oneonta.edu without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need
information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our
online information practices.
SUNY Oneonta does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that
information voluntarily by sending an e‐mail, completing the SUNY Oneonta Information
Request Form, or completing the online application.
This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the
Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.
Information Collected Automatically When You Visit oneonta.edu
When visiting oneonta.edu, SUNY Oneonta automatically collects and stores the following
information about your visit:
    •    The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site
    •    The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is
         running
    •    The Web page from which the user accessed the current Web page
    •    The date and time of the user's request
    •    The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the above‐mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the
Internet Security and Privacy Act . The information that is collected automatically is used to
improve oneonta.edu's content and to help SUNY Oneonta understand how users are
interacting with its Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to
determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not
collected for commercial marketing purposes and SUNY Oneonta is not authorized to sell or
otherwise disclose the information collected from oneonta.edu for commercial marketing
purposes.
Information Collected When You E‐mail oneonta.edu or Complete a Transaction
During your visit to oneonta.edu you may send an e‐mail to the SUNY Oneonta. Your e‐mail
address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not
limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats
included in the message. Your e‐mail address and the information included in your message will
be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to
forward your message to another SUNY Oneonta campus for appropriate action. Your e‐mail
address is not collected for commercial purposes and SUNY Oneonta is not authorized to sell or
otherwise disclose your e‐mail address for commercial purposes.

During your visit to oneonta.edu you may complete a transaction such as an online application
or the SUNY Oneonta Information Request Form. The information collected by SUNY Oneonta,
including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by
SUNY Oneonta and may be disclosed by SUNY Oneonta for those purposes that may be
reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information
was submitted.
SUNY Oneonta does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of
13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the
collection of personal information submitted in an e‐mail will be treated as though it was
submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be
subject to public access.
Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Web site
The collection of information through oneonta.edu and the disclosure of that information are
subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. SUNY Oneonta will only
collect personal information through oneonta.edu or disclose personal information collected
through oneonta.edu if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal
information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to SUNY Oneonta by the user,
constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by SUNY Oneonta for the
purposes for which the user disclosed the information to SUNY Oneonta.
However, SUNY Oneonta may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the
collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of SUNY Oneonta, or
necessary for SUNY Oneonta to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or
federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose
of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical
purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.
Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through
oneonta.edu is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal
Privacy Protection Law.
SUNY Oneonta may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement
authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access
to SUNY Oneonta’s information technology assets.
Retention of Information Collected Through this Web site
The information collected through oneonta.edu is retained by SUNY Oneonta in accordance with
the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs
Law. Information on the requirements of the Arts & Cultural Affairs Law may be found at
http://home.att.net/~allanmcnyc/art_laws.html. Information concerning these records
retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact
listed in this policy.
Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through this site
Any user may submit a request to SUNY Oneonta's privacy compliance officer to determine
whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through oneonta.edu.

Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of
identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature,
inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification.
The address of the privacy compliance officer is:
                 Carol A. Blazina
                 Privacy Compliance Officer
                 301 Netzer Administration Building
                 State University of New York College at Oneonta
                 Ravine Parkway
                 Oneonta, NY 13820
                  (607) 436‐2748
The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper
request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining the
reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate
date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30)
days from the date of the acknowledgment.
In the event that SUNY Oneonta has collected personal information pertaining to a user through
oneonta.edu and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user’s request,
the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the
personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of
the Public Officers Law.
Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through oneonta.edu
SUNY Oneonta is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through
oneonta.edu against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, SUNY Oneonta
limits employee access to personal information collected through oneonta.edu to only those
employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties.
Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection
with any disclosures of personal information.
In addition, SUNY Oneonta has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its
information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization,
monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the
design, implementation, and day‐to‐day operations of oneonta.edu as part of our continuing
commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of
information.
For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of oneonta.edu for all users,
SUNY Oneonta employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload
or change information or otherwise damage oneonta.edu.
Cookies
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the user's browser on the hard drive
of your computer. Oneonta.edu does not use cookies.

Disclaimer
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal,
or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through
oneonta.edu.
Contact Information
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e‐mail
at blazinca@oneonta.edu or by regular mail at:
         Carol A. Blazina
         Privacy Compliance Officer
         301 Netzer Administration Building
         State University of New York College at Oneonta
         Ravine Parkway
         Oneonta, NY 13820
         (607) 436‐2748
Definitions
The following definitions apply to, and appear in italics, in this policy:
         Personal information: For purposes of this policy, “personal information” means any
         information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol,
         mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.
         User: shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State
         Technology Law
Approved by the President’s Cabinet May 14, 2002
